

# Chok Eu Tjin | Web Developer

I am an enthusiastic and driven Web Developer who likes creating things and solving problems. Programming is my passion, and I aim to collaborate with other like-minded developers. I have extensive experience working with diverse individuals/teams and firmly think that progress is made via teamwork. I am interested in both front-end and back-end web development opportunities.

22 Sept. 1991

010 8028 6105

Seoul, Korea

🔀 eutjin\_72@hotmail.com

Malaysia

https://eutjin-dev.com • https://github.com/eutjin

# Skills

**Programming Languages** Javascript (ES6), HTML, CSS

**Libraries and Frameworks** 

React, NodeJS, Express, MantineUI

**Database** 

MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Git, Netlify, Digital Ocean, Figma, Photoshop, Lightroom

### **Education**

### **Master of Engineering Science**

Universiti Tunku Abdul Rahman (UTAR), Malaysia June 2014 - June 2017

### **Research Topic:**

A Novel Algorithm for Optimal Operation and Sizing of Generator-Photovoltaic-Energy Storage System for Minimizing Cost of Energy

Link | PDF

### Research publications:

1.) Novel fuzzy-based control strategy for standalone power systems for minimum cost of electricity in rural areas

Link | PDF

2.) Control Strategies in Energy Storage System for Standalone Power Systems

Link | PDF

3.) Innovative Fuzzy Controller on Island Power Systems with Energy Storage and Renewable for Minimum Fuel Consumption

Link | PDF

# **Bachelor of Electrical and Electronics Engineering (Degree)**

Universiti Tunku Abdul Rahman (UTAR), Malaysia June 2010 - June 2014

#### **Awards:**

1.) Innovate Malaysia Design Competiton 2014 **National Instruments track: Grand Prize** 

Energy Link: An Interactive Energy Management Platform | URL

2.) Fifth Technopreneurship and Innovation Symposium and Exhibition (TISE) 2013 Young Intellectual category Winner

Dr Energy: a plug-and-play, multifunctional electrical power diagnostic platform | URL

# **Work Experience**

# 1. Technical Support Specialist | Quality Team

GOQUAL Inc. (Korea), May 2018 - Current

I joined the IoT startup as the 6th member and have subsequently handled various responsibilities. My work positions need me to continually address problems and communicate with both internal and external teams.

## Technical Support (Chief Specialist)

- Provide in-depth technical support to the customer service (CS) team
- Design and implement problem solving process flow which enables the CS team to serve end-users in a shorter time period (30% reduction in average engagement time with users)
- Provide technical training to employees on product technologies and various product trouble-shooting methods

# Quality Control and Assurance (QC/QA)

- APP and device firmware testing: investigate APP/device-related issues and submit issue report to software developers.
- Product quality issue/defects: analyze issue and notify manufacturers so that improvements may be made and future occurrences are prevented
- Manual QA testing of iOS and AOS APPs prior to every APP updates.
- providing services to 480,000 total registered users, 460,000 activated devices
- 240,000 monthly active users (MAU) and 140,000 Daily Active Users (DAU)

### **Product Sourcing and Production Management**

- · Directly involved in the sourcing, development, production and launching of over ten different IoT devices into the Korean market (currently a market leader in the IoT field)
- Develop systematic product testing and validation processes to ensure the best products are released in a short Time to Market period
- Communicate product issues with technical teams from multiple manufacturers and factories prior to product release

#### 2. Research Intern

Remotec Technology Ltd. (Hong Kong), July 2017 - January 2018

- · Research project on control algorithm to enable intelligent operation of air conditioners with the aim to reduce energy consumption while maintaining user comfort levels
- proposed various algorithms which were used by the Research & Development team for product improvement

#### 3. Research Assistant

Universiti Tunku Abdul Rahman (UTAR), Oct. 2014 - Oct. 2016

- Energy Management System (EMS) was successfully installed in a university building and energy savings were achieved
- Proposed an energy control algorithm which was successfully used in the EMS

#### **Projects**

- Gunaesik (React, NodeJS/Express, MongoDB) | URL
- Enerlyzr (React, NodeJS/Express) | URL
- MoviReVue (React, NodeJS/Express, MongoDB) | URL

\*Detailed info available at https://eutjin-dev.com/#projects